Milos Vasic, curriculum vitae



About

Software Engineer from Belgrade, Serbia. In software development since 2009. Experience with full software development lifecycle from planning, development, team leading to the final deployment to production.

Speaking languages: Serbian and English. Also Russian with basic understanding without speaking.

The main development technology

- Android, JetPack Compose, MVVP, Kotlin Flow, Kotlin Coroutines, Live Data, Retrofit, OkHttp, Firebase, Dagger, Hilt, etc.
- Kotlin Multiplatform, Kotlin, Kotlin Coroutines
- React Native, Expo, Npm, Yarn
- Flutter (Dart)
- iOS with Swift (Legacy and Swift UI)

Work experience

Through the career have been working on the various projects and with various clients.

Fulltime positions

 Harness - Belgrade, Serbia (full-time), from 03/2020 until 12/2024, Staff Software Engineer (various technologies)

- Leica Geosystems Heerbrugg, Switzerland (full-time), from 02/2016 until 02/2020, Android and iOS Developer (with C++ core)
- Bosch Belgrade, Serbia (full-time), from 01/2010 until 01/2016, Android SDK Developer

Other projects involved

- TN-TECH Novi Sad, Serbia (part-time), from 03/2017
 - o Globex Data (Canada and Switzerland): Sekur (SekurMessenger), SekurMail, SekurSuite
 - BusRide platform
- Increment Loop Belgrade, Serbia (part-time), from 09/2023
 - Yuno
- HelixTrack
- Server Factory
 - Mail Server Factory
 - o Parallels Utils
 - Qemu Utils
- Android Toolkit

Other technology

Also familiar with the following technology:

Desktop development

- Electron
- Java (Swing and Fx)
- C++ (QT with Qmake or Cmake with Ninja and Konan)
- Flutter (Desktop)
- React Native (Desktop)
- Kotlin Multiplatform (Desktop)
- macOS with Swift

Backend development

- GoLang (Gin Gonic)
- Java and Kotlin (Spring / Spring Boot with Maven and Gradle)
- Python (Pyramid, Flask with Waitress)
- Ruby (Ruby on Rails)
- C++ (Drogon with Cmake, Ninja and Konan)
- Docker, Docker Compose

Web development

- React
- Angular
- JavaScript and TypeScript
- HTML, CSS

Data and Databases

- PostgreSQL
- MySQL
- Sqlite
- Firebase
- MongoDB
- Redis
- Apache Kafka
- RabbitMQ

Various

- Bash
- Git, SVN, Perforce
- GitHub (with Copilot) GitLab, GitFlic, Gitee, Gitverse
- Gradle, MVN, CMake, Ninja, etc.
- JIRA, Confluence, Active Collab
- Jenkins, Travis, Circle CI, Bitbucket Pipelines, GitHub Actions, All from Harness
- macOS, Linux, Microsoft Windows
- All JetBrains IDEs, GIGA IDE, VSCode, etc.
- XCode
- REST API, WebSockets, SIP, Matrix, SSDP, Quic, etc.
- SonarQube

Author work

Worked on several programming books as self-published author and author for Packt Publishing UK.

Self-published: Fundamental Kotlin, Last edition: Fundamental-Kotlin: revised (September 6, 2022.)

Education

- Bachelor of Science: Informatics and Computing, 2008. University Singidunum, Belgrade (Serbia)
- M.Sc: Contemporary Information Technologies, 2014. University Singidunum, Belgrade (Serbia)

Contacts and links

- E-Mail: i@mvasic.ru
- Mobile: +381 69 25 35 718 (Serbia), +7 966 323 77 17 (Russian Federation)
- Telegram: milos85vasic
- Networks: Linkedin, TenChat, Xing, VK
- Source code and Open-Source: GitHub, GitFlic, Gitee